<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fantasy on Elise Volkman</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fantasy on Elise Volkman</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fantasy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Spines Ya Crackin&#39;? 📚 (BOOK spines, that is)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-spines-ya-crackin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-spines-ya-crackin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Book spines! I swear I meant BOOK spines! I get that I&amp;rsquo;m a fantasy author with a penchant for the darker tales (though you cannot accuse me of publishing any tragedies, those will never see beyond the deep, dark reaches of a digital filing cabinet). But come ON.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s now 2024. The last time I updated anyone on my reading progress was last year, when I had read 26 books in the first quarter of 2023. My dismal math skills aside, this was a shock to me. And by the end of the final quarter of 2023, we were sitting pretty at &amp;hellip; 🥁 🥁 🥁 &amp;hellip; 90! This is quite the adjustment from my original January plan to read (&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;checks notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) exactly ONE book per month. One. 1. Uno. Un. Not two. Not three. Not zero. One.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Soft Magic Systems Are So Hard to Write 🪄</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hard-and-soft-magic-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hard-and-soft-magic-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me two attempts to finish reading &lt;em&gt;For the Throne&lt;/em&gt; by Hannah Whitten. At first, I thought I was just bored because the book started off with different POV characters. But in the end, the thing that was really bothering me was the magic system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soft and hard magic systems are like the difference between Star Wars and &lt;em&gt;Project Hail Mary&lt;/em&gt;. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite space opera is pretty approachable even if you don&amp;rsquo;t care a lick about science, while &lt;em&gt;Project Hail Mary&lt;/em&gt;, from the author of &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt;, will only appeal to those who are willing to learn about the nitty gritty details of the science at play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet My New Favourite Author, Plus a Few More 📚</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/meet-my-new-favourite-author-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/meet-my-new-favourite-author-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crows, security robots, seas made of spores, and a subspecies of dragon called a quigutl. Yes, dear friends. You&amp;rsquo;re in for a whole lot of &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; this quarter. If you need any reading material, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you going for a while. My goal was to read 24 books by the end of this year — that&amp;rsquo;s one each month, in case you hate math as much as I do. Reason being, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling like reading much at all for a while and didn&amp;rsquo;t think I could manage much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Few More Good Reads: Happy New Year! 🥂</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:30:44 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/happy-new-year-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I sat down to pick out my top reads of the last quarter of 2022, I looked at my list and thought to myself, &amp;ldquo;Well, this looks a lot more like me.&amp;rdquo; And yet, as I write this, I feel less like myself than I ever have. Aren&amp;rsquo;t people funny paradoxes? Funny isn&amp;rsquo;t the right word, but we use it like that all the time. Funny can mean can mean odd, unsettling, and uncomfortable. But at face value, it&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; funny.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Round-Up — September 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reading-round-up-september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reading-round-up-september-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-winternight-trilogy&#34;&gt;Skip to the books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;slowing-down-but-never-stopping&#34;&gt;Slowing Down But Never Stopping&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In August, I popped in here to talk about &amp;ldquo;good writing.&amp;rdquo; By that, I meant the three books I had read that year that made me say &amp;ldquo;I want to write like that one day.&amp;rdquo; (That&amp;rsquo;s the author&amp;rsquo;s version of &amp;ldquo;I want to be like them when I grow up.&amp;rdquo;) Since then, I have read eight books. Is that a lot? Eight books in two months? I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a lot for some people, and not a lot for some, but it&amp;rsquo;s a lot more than I expected from myself this year. In January alone, I read eight books, so by that count, I&amp;rsquo;d have to say I&amp;rsquo;ve slowed down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nymph Keepers is over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does that ever feel good to say! But I think it&amp;rsquo;s also a challenge, to move on from a project that big and fill that space with something new. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong; I haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped writing other drafts and working other stories, so there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of projects. But this is a bit of a goodbye — a transition from one season into another, or from one focus toward something new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find Out How the Story Ends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/queen-of-the-nymphs-launch-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 07:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/queen-of-the-nymphs-launch-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-launch-day&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Launch Day&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have no trouble believing this, but I&amp;rsquo;m still in a bit of a daze: &lt;em&gt;Queen of the Nymphs&lt;/em&gt; is here! Today is the day and Book III of the Nymph Keepers is ready and waiting for you. You can find out how the story ends &lt;a href=&#34;https://books2read.com/queenofthenymphs&#34;&gt;wherever ebooks are sold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But wait!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-made-you-a-treat&#34;&gt;I Made You a Treat&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough to do, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d treat you to something a little extra special: Chapters 1 &amp;amp; 2 of &lt;em&gt;Queen of the Nymphs&lt;/em&gt;, read by yours truly. (Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t consider that a treat, in which case, feel free to read those chapters all by yourself! But if you like listening to people read&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Writing: My Top 3 Reads of 2022 (So Far)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/good-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 12:33:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/good-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1-an-enchantment-of-ravens-by-margaret-rogerson&#34;&gt;An Enchantment of Ravens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#2-if-we-were-villains-by-ml-rio&#34;&gt;If We Were Villains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#3-the-love-hypothesis-by-ali-hazelwood&#34;&gt;The Love Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-read-or-not-to-read&#34;&gt;To Read or Not To Read&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can count on one hand the number of books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year that have made me want to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt;. And I&amp;rsquo;ve read 30 books so far. Maybe those aren&amp;rsquo;t great odds. Maybe I should be more selective about the books I pick up; maybe I should DNF (did-not-finish) more often. But once I start reading something, I have an excruciatingly hard time stopping until I reach &amp;ldquo;The End.&amp;rdquo; If I consider stopping because I&amp;rsquo;m not enjoying it, I invariably end up feeling guilty. &lt;em&gt;Am I just not in the right mood for it? Am I in a bad headspace with writing at the moment, and I&amp;rsquo;m taking it out on this poor author?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heart of the Forest, A Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/heart-of-the-forest-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 12:15:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/heart-of-the-forest-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;spoilers-for-heart-of-the-forest-ahead&#34;&gt;SPOILERS FOR HEART OF THE FOREST AHEAD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the start of Heart of the Forest: Book II of the Nymph Keepers, the war between Ireece and Galia has just begun, sparked by the death of the ambassador — the Nymph Keeper — who Jay killed. Meanwhile, a new plot unravels in Fethens, threatening to unravel Forest’s life as court herbalist: Silic and Protis secretly poison the king of Ireece with Hellfire in a zealous attempt to put Terryn on the throne.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roots of Blood, A Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/roots-of-blood-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 12:06:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/roots-of-blood-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;spoilers-for-roots-of-blood-ahead&#34;&gt;SPOILERS FOR ROOTS OF BLOOD AHEAD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After Jay saves Forest from the Butcher — the Nymph Keeper he had originally been working for in order to get the nymph blood he needed to help his sister — he takes her to his home city of Fethens. Forest expected this to be just another stop in a life of horrors. She tries to escape to the mountains, where she finds the rumoured mountain nymphs and hopes for refuge, but as a forest nymph, she cannot survive underground. After Silic brings her back to the city of Fethens, he introduces Forest to his found family of nymphs, and she begins to feel more at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Queen of the Nymphs, Available for Pre-Order!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/queen-of-the-nymphs-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/queen-of-the-nymphs-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;releasing-august-12th&#34;&gt;Releasing August 12th…&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the final book of The Nymph Keepers, Forest struggles with her duties as court herbalist and the expectations of a future queen as the rot ravaging Galia’s lands creeps over the borders into the other provinces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books2read.com/queenofthenymphs&#34;&gt;And pre-orders are now OPEN.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s right. After weeks (months) of saying “soon,” I’m here to tell you that Queen of the Nymphs is HERE. And in the words of The Incredibles, “It’s bigger… [and] It’s better!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
