<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editing on Elise Volkman</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/editing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editing on Elise Volkman</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/editing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fine Arts Hasn&#39;t Killed Me Yet 👀</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fine-arts-hasnt-killed-me-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fine-arts-hasnt-killed-me-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fall 2023 and Winter 2024 have gone down in history. In the last eight months, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to finish drafting and revising a 107,000 word fantasy novel; designed, printed, and celebrated the launch of a literary magazine of student art; and signed at least two new freelance contracts with hopes for at least one or two more for Summer 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feast your eyes&amp;hellip; 👀&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;gallery-box&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/book-reviews/louden-2024-1.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/book-reviews/louden-2024-2.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/book-reviews/louden-2024-3.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought going on hiatus from freelance contracts was going to eviscerate the tenuous career I began building for myself in 2019. But as I shared with a friend the other day, as soon as the end of my Winter 2024 semester hit, I had opportunities flying at me seemingly from every corner. These opportunities were all connected in one way or another to seeds planted in past weeks, months, or years, but nevertheless they appeared when I felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even trying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Editor Is on Hiatus! 💜</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-editor-is-on-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-editor-is-on-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t be taking on new clients for the foreseeable future because &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m back in school! Didn&amp;rsquo;t see that coming (said no one, literally ever).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I told my husband I was done with school for &amp;ldquo;a good while&amp;rdquo; after I finished my editing certificate in 2022, he laughed at me. I defended myself. I&amp;rsquo;d been in school for the past 6 years with no break and only a couple certificates to show for it. I said couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand the idea of being in school again any time soon. I wanted a good, long break.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editing Reflections: Slowing Down &amp; Catching Up 📚</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/editing-reflections-q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/editing-reflections-q2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelancing seasons cycle between feast or famine so quickly, it can be disorienting to try and look back at what the past few months have held. On the rollercoaster of &amp;ldquo;How much work do I have this month?&amp;rdquo; I went from slowing down at the end of March to busy enough to make my head spin from April to May. And then by June, things were winding down again. The forecast for July looks dry as well, and then promise of showers for August. By September, my whole schedule will change around, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpectedly Expected: 2022 Editing Update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unexpectedly-expected-editing-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 15:35:44 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unexpectedly-expected-editing-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life really does not go the way we expect it to sometimes, does it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We like to say that a lot. We acknowledge the unexpected as a natural part of life and like to make it sound like we&amp;rsquo;re all aware of how uncertain things can be. But then, when something inevitably doesn&amp;rsquo;t go our way, &lt;strong&gt;PANIC!&lt;/strong&gt; at the Disco.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you asked me today, I would probably say that life is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going my way most of the time. And this is both good and bad news because sometimes those surprises are necessary for growth. Sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re pleasant things, sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re not, and I&amp;rsquo;m not always the best person to make a judgement call on that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Types of Editing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/types-of-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 21:41:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/types-of-editing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-start&#34;&gt;Where to Start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Editing has many facets, but it tends to be narrowed down to just one: rules. Grammar, punctuation, typos — it’s the first thing we look for when someone asks us to read through the tricky email, announcement, or advertisement they’re writing. Rules are straightforward. They present a clear right and wrong, and as long as you abide by them, you should be fine. Right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem with language, and English is just as bad for this as any other language, is that the rules are never simple. There are exceptions to every rule and the rules change over time as languages become modernized, words take on new meanings, and old sayings lose their effectiveness. The role of an editor becomes about so much more than catching a stray typo and fixing the tense of a verb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
